<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetadata xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <Name>Stationpedia Ascended</Name>
  <Author>FlorpyDorp</Author>
  <Version>0.8.7</Version>
  <Description>This is a Plugin Mod. It requires BepInEx to be installed with the StationeersLaunchPad plugin.
See: https://github.com/StationeersLaunchPad/StationeersLaunchPad

An enhanced Stationpedia experience with comprehensive tooltips, in-game notepad, guides, bug fixes, and quality of life improvements. Stationpedia on a new level.

NEW IN 0.8.7:
- Fix: Closing the Station Notepad no longer removes your mouse cursor when another window (Stationpedia, in-game menu) is still open

NEW IN 0.8.6:
- Search Fixes: Cable Coil, Corn, and other items now appear correctly in search
- Search: "Starts With" category properly shows all matching items
- Search: Partial word matches properly demoted, performance optimized
- Code: Consolidated dual init paths eliminating Workshop vs ScriptEngine feature drift
- Header title reliably shows "Stationpedia Ascended" on first load
- Debug: Centralized logging system for development builds

Features:
- Enhanced Tooltips: Hover over logic types, slots, memory, modes, and connections
- Operational Details: Dedicated section showing advanced device information
- In-Game Notepad: Take notes that persist across game sessions (F2 to toggle)
- Comprehensive Guides: Survival, Power, Airlock, AC, and more
- Bug Fixes: Fixed scrollbar handle and window dragging crashes

All tooltips and descriptions are customizable via descriptions.json.

Discord: https://discord.gg/stationeers</Description>

  <ChangeLog>
v0.8.7: Hotfix - Notepad cursor
- FIX Station Notepad: closing the notepad no longer removes your mouse cursor when another window (Stationpedia, in-game menu) is still open. The notepad now registers as a proper game modal so the cursor is managed by the game.
v0.8.6: Search Fixes &amp; Code Consolidation
- FIX Search: Cable Coil, Corn, and other items now appear correctly in search results
- FIX Search: Items hidden by HideInStationpedia no longer incorrectly excluded from search
- FIX Search: "Starts With" category now properly shows all matching items
- FIX Search: Partial word matches properly demoted in results
- OPT Search: Single-pass bucketing, caching, pre-allocated lists for faster ordering
- FIX Code: Consolidated dual init paths (ScriptEngine vs SLP/Workshop)
- FIX Code: Header title reliably shows "Stationpedia Ascended" on first load
- FIX Code: Logo icon enlarged and repositioned to avoid text overlap
- NEW Debug: Centralized debug logging system with SPDA_DEBUG toggle
v0.8.5: Content &amp; Notepad Improvements
- FIX Station Notepad: Input now properly locks keyboard while typing
- FIX Station Notepad: Enter key no longer opens chat while editing
- FIX Station Notepad: JSON documents display correctly on hotload
- NEW Species Survival Guide: Lung damage and suffocation mechanics from game code
- NEW Species Survival Guide: Mood &amp; Hygiene section with thresholds and effects
- FIX Content: Corrected gas terminology (no X3/X1, using Volatiles/Pollutant/Hydrogen)
- NEW Editor: Import JSON button for importing guide files
- NEW Editor: Drag-and-drop to move content between categories
- NEW Editor: Inline section headers within categories
- FIX In-Game: Guides and mechanics display in correct JSON order
v0.8.0: Major Feature Release - Station Notepad, Guides, Media Support
- NEW Station Notepad: In-game note-taking with folders, rich text, Stationpedia links
- NEW Survival Manual: Complete beginner's guide (First 5 Minutes to Advanced)
- NEW Game Mechanics: Smelting Guide and Species Survival Guide from game code
- NEW Media Support: Embed videos and images in Stationpedia pages
- NEW Nested TOC: Multi-level table of contents with smooth scrolling
- Vanilla/Ascended Mode: Click header to toggle (easter egg)
- Multiple guides: Power Systems, Airlock, Air Conditioning, Daylight Sensor
v0.3.0: AIMeE documentation, multi-column TOC, new JSON schema features
v0.2.2: Search optimizations, property tooltips, IC10 helpers
v0.2.1: Enhanced search with smart grouping, visual headers, debris filtering
v0.1.x: Initial releases with tooltips, operational details, bug fixes</ChangeLog>
  <WorkshopHandle>3634225688</WorkshopHandle>
  <Tags>
    <Tag>StationeersLaunchPad</Tag>
    <Tag>UI</Tag>
    <Tag>Helper</Tag>
    <Tag>QualityOfLife</Tag>
    <Tag>BugFix</Tag>
  </Tags>
  <InGameDescription><![CDATA[<size="30"><color=#ffa500>Stationpedia Ascended</color></size>
<color=#ff0000>This is a Plugin Mod. It requires BepInEx to be installed with the StationeersLaunchPad plugin.</color>
See: https://github.com/StationeersLaunchPad/StationeersLaunchPad

An enhanced Stationpedia experience with in-game notepad, comprehensive guides, tooltips, and quality of life improvements.

<color=#ffa500>What's New in 0.8.7:</color>
- Fix: Closing the Station Notepad no longer removes your mouse cursor when another window is still open

<color=#ffa500>0.8.6:</color>
- Search Fixes: Cable Coil, Corn, and other items appear correctly
- Search: Starts With category properly shows all matching items
- Search performance optimized with caching and single-pass bucketing
- Code: Consolidated dual init paths, reliable header on first load

<color=#ffa500>Features:</color>
- Hover tooltips for logic types, slots, memory, modes
- In-game notepad with folders and rich text (F2)
- Comprehensive guides: Survival, Power, Airlock, AC
- Stationpedia links in notes: {LINK:DeviceKey;Text}
- Fixes for scrollbar handle and window dragging bugs
- Click "Stationpedia" header for Ascended mode

All content customizable via descriptions.json.
]]></InGameDescription>
</ModMetadata>
