<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetadata xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <Name>AIMeE Bug Fixes</Name>
  <Author>FlorpyDorp</Author>
  <Version>0.15.3</Version>
  <WorkshopHandle>3674960841</WorkshopHandle>
  <Description>This is a Plugin Mod. It requires BepInEx to be installed with the StationeersLaunchPad plugin.
See: https://github.com/StationeersLaunchPad/StationeersLaunchPad

Fixes fourteen bugs with the AIMeE mining robot:

1. Mine Deadlock: AIMeE stops mining after first ore because _mineCancellation is never reset after Mine() completes.
2. Off-State Teleporting: When turned off but receiving logic, AIMeE hops/teleports because TryUnstuck/PathToTarget have no OnOff guard.
3. Tread Animation Desync: On dedicated server clients, tread UV animations are frozen because WheelRpm is never set on non-authority clients.
4. Roam Regression: AIMeE stops exploring when no ore is in scan range because driving logic is skipped when queue is empty. Also restores MinableSearchArea from 16 to 32.
5. Pickup Launch: Picking up/dragging AIMeE launches the player because wheel motor torque transfers through the drag joint.
6. MineablesInQueue Client Sync: MineablesInQueue always reads 0 on multiplayer clients because the queue is a local server-only list.
7. MineablesInVicinity Overcount: Vicinity count includes ore from entire veins beyond the search area due to missing per-ore bounds check.
8. Carry Collision Launch: Carrying AIMeE and bumping terrain/objects launches the player because WheelCollider suspension forces transfer through the drag joint.
9. Stuck Teleporting: When stuck for 60 seconds, Unstuck() teleports AIMeE by directly writing position. Replaced with physics-based escape (backward impulse + random torque). Also adds velocity-based stuck detection to catch AIMeEs pushing against each other.
10. Distant Ore Selection: AIMeEs mine far-away ore instead of closest. Queue now sorted by distance so nearest ore is mined first.
11. Circling Fix: AIMeEs circle aimlessly due to stuck detection feedback loop. Added post-reverse cooldown, mild steering reset after reversing, and reduced reverse duration. Also reduced queue cap from 10 to 5 for better multi-AIMeE ore sharing.
12. Ghost Ore Fix: Ore mined by AIMeE stays visible on multiplayer clients. Fixed by injecting a VoxelChangeEvent directly into the SyncList, bypassing SetDensityWorldSpace entirely. Zero server-side terrain work. Client receives the event and calls MineAtPositionClient to remove the ore. Works for all surface ore visible to players.
13. Underground Ore Fix: AIMeE targets ore deep underground in tunnels and caves. The surface check (IsNearSurface) only tests a single voxel 3 blocks above the ore. In a tunnel, that point is empty, so underground ore passes the check. Fixed with a column scan that detects cave ceilings — if solid terrain exists above an empty gap, the ore is rejected as unreachable.
14. Stale Queue Fix: AIMeE's ore queue is never cleared when picked up, turned on, or given a TargetXYZ. Stale entries point to ore at old locations and block other AIMeEs via AllAimeeQueuedMinables. Fixed by clearing the queue on pickup, power-on, and TargetX/Y/Z writes.

Debug overlay now shows [SERVER]/[REMOTE] labels and displays client-appropriate data on dedicated servers.

Works on both dedicated servers and clients.</Description>

  <ChangeLog><![CDATA[
v0.15.3: Bug 12 improved — two-event approach (no terrain holes)
- Bug 12: Previous fix (density 0) carved visible holes in terrain on clients
- Now uses two VoxelChangeEvents per mine: event 1 (density 0) removes ore,
  event 2 (original density) restores terrain. Ore gone, terrain intact.
- Server terrain still completely unmodified

v0.15.2: Bug 12 improved — fix ghost ore for subsurface mining
- Bug 12: Send density 0 in VoxelChangeEvent instead of current density
- Ore 1-3 blocks below surface has solid density (>= 127), which failed ShouldReleaseMinables
- MineAtPositionClient never fired on clients — ghost ore persisted
- Now always sends density 0: client carves terrain + removes ore model (same as player mining)
- Server terrain unmodified — only SyncList is touched
- Client visual hole is cosmetic, resets on reconnect

v0.15.1: Bug 13 improved — increased cave scan height
- Bug 13: Increased IsNearSurface scan height from 20 to 64 blocks
- Tall caves (17+ blocks) were fooling the scan — ceiling not found within 20 blocks
- 64 blocks covers all realistic Stationeers terrain depths
- Ore in tall natural caves and player-dug caverns now correctly rejected

v0.15.0: Bug 14 — Stale queue fix
- Bug 14: Queue now clears when AIMeE is picked up, turned on, or given TargetXYZ
- Prevents stale ore entries pointing to old locations after relocation
- Frees AllAimeeQueuedMinables hash entries so other AIMeEs can claim ore
- Detected via UpdateEachFrame state tracking (IsCursor, OnOff transitions)
- TargetX/Y/Z writes detected via SetLogicValue postfix

v0.14.0: Bug 12 improved — direct SyncList injection
- Bug 12: Replaced density-passthrough with direct VoxelChangeEvent SyncList injection
- Bypasses SetDensityWorldSpace entirely — zero server-side terrain work
- No octree modification, no UpdateCanAirPass, no DirtyLods on server
- Client receives event, calls MineAtPositionClient — ore model disappears
- Cleaner, faster, and no voxel density changes anywhere

v0.13.0: Bug 12 proper fix — density-passthrough approach
- Bug 12: Ghost ore now disappears on clients WITHOUT modifying terrain
- Reads current voxel density at ore position and re-sets it to same value
- Creates VoxelChangeEvent (client sync) without changing any terrain
- For surface ore (density < 50%): sync triggers MineAtPositionClient on clients
- For buried ore (density >= 50%): invisible to players, self-heals on terrain mining or rejoin
- No more terrain destruction from v0.12.0

v0.12.2: CRITICAL — Remove all terrain voxel modification
- Removed ALL SetDensityWorldSpace calls — AIMeE must never modify terrain
- Bug 12 (ghost ore) patch DISABLED — the game's client sync mechanism (VoxelChangeEvent) inherently modifies terrain density, which destroys the ground under/around ore
- AIMeE only picks up surface ore via TryMineServer, no terrain digging
- Ghost ore on clients is cosmetic; terrain destruction is gameplay-breaking

v0.12.1: Cliff-climbing regression fix
- Fix: AIMeE can climb steep terrain again — velocity-based stuck detection now also checks position delta
- Stuck detection only triggers reverse if position moved < 0.5m over 5 seconds (rules out slow climbing)
- Previously, climbing a cliff at low velocity falsely triggered stuck→reverse loop every 5 seconds

v0.12.0: Bug 12 re-fix + Roam distance improvement
- Bug 12: Multi-pronged ghost ore fix — calls SetDensityWorldSpace in OnMinedOre postfix (catches all mining paths) AND before TryMineServer in Roam prefix (matches Quarry pattern)
- Bug 12: TryMineServer postfix kept as belt-and-suspenders with unconditional logging
- Bug 12: Uses TargetMinable position via GetMinableWorldPosition for correct voxel coords
- Roam: AIMeE now drives straight for 8-12 seconds before turning (was 1-3s)
- Roam: Steering angle kept at ±30° for good coverage when turning

v0.11.0: Bug 12 + Bug 13 — Ghost ore fix + underground ore fix
- Bug 12: Ore mined by AIMeE now correctly disappears on multiplayer clients
- Bug 12: Postfix on Vein.TryMineServer adds SetDensityWorldSpace(0) for VoxelChangeEvent client sync
- Bug 13: AIMeE no longer targets ore deep underground in tunnels/caves
- Bug 13: Replaced single-voxel surface check with column scan that detects cave ceilings
- Bug 13: Scans up to 20 blocks above ore; rejects if solid→empty→solid pattern found
- Bug 7: Vicinity count now also uses improved Bug 13 surface check

v0.10.0: Bug 12 — Ghost ore client sync fix
- Bug 12: Ore mined by AIMeE now correctly disappears on multiplayer clients
- Bug 12: Postfix on Vein.TryMineServer adds SetDensityWorldSpace(0) to create VoxelChangeEvent for SyncList client sync
- Bug 12: Also fixes the same base game bug in the original Roam() and async Mine() paths

v0.9.0: Bug 11 — Circling fix + debug overlay client/server awareness
- Bug 11: Add post-reverse cooldown (3s) to break stuck→reverse→stuck feedback loops
- Bug 11: Reset steering to mild angle (±5°) when reverse ends (was keeping ±30°)
- Bug 11: Increase stuck detection time from 3s to 5s (less aggressive triggering)
- Bug 11: Reduce velocity-stuck reverse duration from 5s to 3s
- Bug 9: Reduce backward impulse from 2.0 to 1.0 (prevents wheelies)
- Bug 9: Reduce random torque from ±3 to ±2 (less violent spin)
- Bug 9: Reduce Unstuck reverse time from 8s to 5s
- Queue cap reduced from 10 to 5 per AIMeE (better multi-AIMeE ore sharing)
- Debug overlay now shows [SERVER] or [REMOTE] label per AIMeE
- Client overlay shows only available data (vicinity, velocity, mode)
- Client overlay explains that queue/target/motor are server-only

v0.8.0: Bug 9 + Bug 10 — Stuck teleport fix + closest ore selection
- Bug 9: Replace Unstuck() teleport with physics-based escape (backward impulse + random torque)
- Bug 9: Add velocity-based stuck detection in Roam (catches AIMeEs pushing against each other)
- Bug 9: Increase obstacle raycast from 0.2m to 0.5m for earlier obstacle detection
- Bug 9: Randomize steering angle on reverse to break stuck loops
- Bug 10: Sort ore queue by distance — closest ore mined first
- Bug 10: Distance sorting applied before queue cap, so farthest ore is dropped
- Debug overlay now shows reversing state (Rev field)

v0.7.0: Bug 8 — Carry collision launch fix
- Disable WheelColliders when AIMeE is being carried/dragged
- Prevents suspension spring and friction forces from launching the player
- Normal body collisions with walls/terrain still work as expected
- Zero residual motor/brake torque on pickup for clean drop behavior
- Call base DynamicThing.PhysicsUpdate for position tracking while carried

v0.6.1: Silent operation by default
- Gate ALL runtime BepInEx logging behind aimeedebug toggle
- No console output unless debug overlay is explicitly enabled
- Startup/init messages still log once on load

v0.6.0: Vicinity diagnostic overhaul
- Fix overlay showing different MineablesInVicinity than IC chip reads
- Overlay now reads via GetLogicValue (same path as IC) for consistency
- Add Bug7 call tracking: success/error counts visible in overlay
- Add GetLogicValue(MineablesInVicinity) diagnostic postfix logging
- Show both IC and direct vicinity values with MISMATCH detection
- Log vicinity count on mode changes for diagnosing premature returns
- Track vicinity changes in state change detection
- More frequent Bug7 diagnostics (every 5s instead of 10s)
- Always log Bug7 errors immediately (no more throttling)

v0.5.0: Debug overlay system
- Add "aimeedebug" console command + F8 keyboard toggle
- Floating text above each AIMeE with stats (mode, queue, vicinity, target, etc.)
- Global debug panel (AIMeE count, AllAimeeQueuedMinables, time)
- State change detection with logging (mode, queue, mining, target, storage)
- Queue fill diagnostics with leak detection and emergency clear
- Mode 3 periodic logging every 0.5s
- Cached at 2Hz for minimal FPS impact

v0.4.2: Queue estimate cap fix
- Cap MineablesInQueue client estimate to max 10 (queue cap)

v0.4.1: MineablesInQueue client fallback restored
- Re-enable Bug 6 patch for MineablesInQueue on non-authority clients
- Return capped queue estimate (max 10) instead of hard-zero on clients
- Keep dedicated-server authority behavior unchanged (real queue still server-side)

v0.4.0: Full Roam() overhaul + multi-AIMeE fairness
- Replace Bug 4 postfix with full Roam() prefix replacement
- Hybrid old/new flow: queue system + always-drive (never stops on empty queue)
- Cap queue to 10 per AIMeE to prevent AllAimeeQueuedMinables starvation
- Use exact game motor/brake formulas (RocketMath.MapToScale)
- Call original MovingToMineable() for mining state machine
- Mine at position using game's exact TryMineServer flow with queue dequeue

v0.3.0: Bug 7 enabled, Bug 6 removed, roam fix
- Enable Bug 7 MineablesInVicinity bounds-check (was incorrectly disabled)
- Remove Bug 6 fake queue proxy that made MineablesInQueue == MineablesInVicinity
- Improve Bug 4 roam exploration: longer steering persistence (4-8s) to reduce circling
- Keep MinableSearchArea restored to 32 (original value when AIMeE worked well)

v0.2.3: Bug 7 fix + Bug 6 ambiguous method fix
- Fix MineablesInVicinity overcounting ore outside search bounds (Bug 7)
- Fix GetLogicValue ambiguous match error from two-overload resolution (Bug 6)

v0.2.2: Bug 6 fix
- Fix MineablesInQueue always 0 on multiplayer clients (Bug 6)

v0.2.1: Bug 5 fix
- Fix picking up AIMeE launching player into the air (Bug 5)
- Changed UpdateEachFrame from prefix to postfix to preserve view-following

v0.2.0: Bugs 3 and 4
- Fix tread UV animation on multiplayer clients via WheelRpm estimation from velocity (Bug 3)
- Fix server-side AnimateAuthority skipped when occluded (Bug 3)
- Fix Roam regression: restore driving logic when ore queue is empty (Bug 4)
- Restore MinableSearchArea from 16 to 32 (Bug 4)

v0.1.0: Initial release
- Fix mine deadlock: _mineCancellation reset after Mine completes (Bug 1)
- Fix off-state teleporting: skip TryUnstuck/PathToTarget when off (Bug 2)
  ]]></ChangeLog>
  <Tags>
    <Tag>StationeersLaunchPad</Tag>
    <Tag>BugFix</Tag>
    <Tag>Server</Tag>
  </Tags>
  <InGameDescription><![CDATA[<size="30"><color=#ffa500>AIMeE Bug Fixes</color></size>
<color=#ff0000>This is a Plugin Mod. It requires BepInEx with StationeersLaunchPad.</color>

Fixes fourteen AIMeE mining robot bugs:

<color=#ffa500>1. Mine Deadlock</color>
AIMeE stops after first ore because the mining cancellation token is never reset.

<color=#ffa500>2. Off-State Teleporting</color>
When off but receiving logic, AIMeE hops/teleports due to missing power guards.

<color=#ffa500>3. Tread Animation Desync</color>
Tread animations frozen on multiplayer clients. WheelRpm estimated from synced velocity.

<color=#ffa500>4. Roam Regression</color>
AIMeE stops exploring when no ore nearby. Driving logic restored when queue empty. Scan range restored to 32.

<color=#ffa500>5. Pickup Launch</color>
Picking up AIMeE launches the player. Motor/brakes zeroed while dragged.

<color=#ffa500>6. MineablesInQueue (Multiplayer)</color>
Always 0 on clients. Uses terrain query as fallback for non-authority.

<color=#ffa500>7. MineablesInVicinity Overcount</color>
Counts ore beyond search area. Added per-ore bounds check matching queue logic.

<color=#ffa500>8. Carry Collision Launch</color>
Carrying AIMeE near terrain/objects launches player. WheelColliders disabled while carried.

<color=#ffa500>9. Stuck Teleporting</color>
AIMeE teleports when stuck for 60s. Replaced with physics-based reverse + random turn.

<color=#ffa500>10. Distant Ore Selection</color>
AIMeE mines far-away ore first. Queue now sorted by distance — closest ore mined first.

<color=#ffa500>11. Circling Fix</color>
AIMeEs circle aimlessly due to stuck detection feedback loop. Post-reverse cooldown and steering reset break the cycle. Queue cap reduced for multi-AIMeE fairness.

<color=#ffa500>12. Ghost Ore Fix (Multiplayer)</color>
Ore mined by AIMeE stays visible on clients. Fixed by injecting sync event directly — client removes the ore model. Zero terrain modification.

<color=#ffa500>13. Underground Ore Fix</color>
AIMeE targets ore deep underground in tunnels/caves. Column scan now detects cave ceilings and rejects unreachable ore.

<color=#ffa500>14. Stale Queue Fix</color>
AIMeE's ore queue isn't cleared on pickup, power-on, or TargetXYZ set. Stale entries waste time and block other AIMeEs. Queue now resets on relocation.

<color=#888888>Debug overlay shows [SERVER]/[REMOTE] labels. On dedicated server clients, server-only values (queue, target, motor) display as unavailable.</color>
]]></InGameDescription>
</ModMetadata>
