<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetadata xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <Name>AIMeE Bug Fixes</Name>
  <Author>FlorpyDorp</Author>
  <Version>0.4.0</Version>
  <Description>This is a Plugin Mod. It requires BepInEx to be installed with the StationeersLaunchPad plugin.
See: https://github.com/StationeersLaunchPad/StationeersLaunchPad

Fixes seven bugs with the AIMeE mining robot:

1. Mine Deadlock: AIMeE stops mining after first ore because _mineCancellation is never reset after Mine() completes.
2. Off-State Teleporting: When turned off but receiving logic, AIMeE hops/teleports because TryUnstuck/PathToTarget have no OnOff guard.
3. Tread Animation Desync: On dedicated server clients, tread UV animations are frozen because WheelRpm is never set on non-authority clients.
4. Roam Regression: AIMeE stops exploring when no ore is in scan range because driving logic is skipped when queue is empty. Also restores MinableSearchArea from 16 to 32.
5. Pickup Launch: Picking up/dragging AIMeE launches the player because wheel motor torque transfers through the drag joint.
6. MineablesInQueue Client Sync: MineablesInQueue always reads 0 on multiplayer clients because the queue is a local server-only list.
7. MineablesInVicinity Overcount: Vicinity count includes ore from entire veins beyond the search area due to missing per-ore bounds check.

Works on both dedicated servers and clients.</Description>

  <ChangeLog>
v0.4.0: Full Roam() overhaul + multi-AIMeE fairness
- Replace Bug 4 postfix with full Roam() prefix replacement
- Hybrid old/new flow: queue system + always-drive (never stops on empty queue)
- Cap queue to 10 per AIMeE to prevent AllAimeeQueuedMinables starvation
- Use exact game motor/brake formulas (RocketMath.MapToScale)
- Call original MovingToMineable() for mining state machine
- Mine at position using game's exact TryMineServer flow with queue dequeue

v0.3.0: Bug 7 enabled, Bug 6 removed, roam fix
- Enable Bug 7 MineablesInVicinity bounds-check (was incorrectly disabled)
- Remove Bug 6 fake queue proxy that made MineablesInQueue == MineablesInVicinity
- Improve Bug 4 roam exploration: longer steering persistence (4-8s) to reduce circling
- Keep MinableSearchArea restored to 32 (original value when AIMeE worked well)

v0.2.3: Bug 7 fix + Bug 6 ambiguous method fix
- Fix MineablesInVicinity overcounting ore outside search bounds (Bug 7)
- Fix GetLogicValue ambiguous match error from two-overload resolution (Bug 6)

v0.2.2: Bug 6 fix
- Fix MineablesInQueue always 0 on multiplayer clients (Bug 6)

v0.2.1: Bug 5 fix
- Fix picking up AIMeE launching player into the air (Bug 5)
- Changed UpdateEachFrame from prefix to postfix to preserve view-following

v0.2.0: Bugs 3 and 4
- Fix tread UV animation on multiplayer clients via WheelRpm estimation from velocity (Bug 3)
- Fix server-side AnimateAuthority skipped when occluded (Bug 3)
- Fix Roam regression: restore driving logic when ore queue is empty (Bug 4)
- Restore MinableSearchArea from 16 to 32 (Bug 4)

v0.1.0: Initial release
- Fix mine deadlock: _mineCancellation reset after Mine completes (Bug 1)
- Fix off-state teleporting: skip TryUnstuck/PathToTarget when off (Bug 2)
  </ChangeLog>
  <Tags>
    <Tag>StationeersLaunchPad</Tag>
    <Tag>BugFix</Tag>
    <Tag>Server</Tag>
  </Tags>
  <InGameDescription><![CDATA[<size="30"><color=#ffa500>AIMeE Bug Fixes</color></size>
<color=#ff0000>This is a Plugin Mod. It requires BepInEx with StationeersLaunchPad.</color>

Fixes seven AIMeE mining robot bugs:

<color=#ffa500>1. Mine Deadlock</color>
AIMeE stops after first ore because the mining cancellation token is never reset.

<color=#ffa500>2. Off-State Teleporting</color>
When off but receiving logic, AIMeE hops/teleports due to missing power guards.

<color=#ffa500>3. Tread Animation Desync</color>
Tread animations frozen on multiplayer clients. WheelRpm estimated from synced velocity.

<color=#ffa500>4. Roam Regression</color>
AIMeE stops exploring when no ore nearby. Driving logic restored when queue empty. Scan range restored to 32.

<color=#ffa500>5. Pickup Launch</color>
Picking up AIMeE launches the player. Motor/brakes zeroed while dragged.

<color=#ffa500>6. MineablesInQueue (Multiplayer)</color>
Always 0 on clients. Uses terrain query as fallback for non-authority.

<color=#ffa500>7. MineablesInVicinity Overcount</color>
Counts ore beyond search area. Added per-ore bounds check matching queue logic.
]]></InGameDescription>
</ModMetadata>
